<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ben Dodson's Blog - Freelance iPhone Developer and WallaBee Founder</title>
    <link>https://bendodson.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://bendodson.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>The weblog of Ben Dodson, iOS Developer and WallaBee Founder</description>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 12:57:19 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 12:57:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>

    
    <item>
      <title>Solcaster</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2018/07/02/solcaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2018/07/02/solcaster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to announce the release of a new client app I’ve been working on for the last few weeks: &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/solcaster/id1387772375?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;Solcaster&lt;/a&gt;, the reverse weather app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2018/solcaster.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;468&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked as the only iOS developer on Solcaster for Reidefine LLC working remotely from the UK. The app is an interesting concept in that it helps you find weather you might be looking for rather than telling you what the weather is like right now. When you open the app, you can choose the type of weather you are looking for, the area you are searching from, and the maximum amount of travelling you are willing to do. It then runs this through a sophisticated algorithm of my own design to show you where you can find that weather. This is useful for a wide range of people be they searching for sun, snow, storms, wind, or even rain&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:rain&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:rain&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve found an area you are interested in, Solcaster provides even more information including the previous and future weather&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:previousfuture&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:previousfuture&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, interesting hikes and climbs, and any events that may be in the local area. This is all powered by a number of APIs with an intelligent caching layer that makes requests as fast and responsive as possible. In addition, there are deeply customisable settings including temperature thresholds, wind speeds, snow accumulation, and of course the option to choose between Celsius and Fahrenheit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is written entirely in Swift 4.1 and is optimised for all iPhone sizes including the relatively new iPhone X. There are a number of interesting Apple technologies being used including iCloud sync which helps keep the settings the same across all of your devices as well as syncing your favourited trips and recent searches. Whilst the app is free to download, it is limited to searching within a 1 hour radius and does contain ads from Admob. For a single in-app purchase of $1.99, the ads are removed and the radius can be extended up to 8 hours. This unlock is also synced automatically through iCloud sync so that you don’t ever need to hit the “restore purchases” button that is ubiquitious with in-app purchases&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:restore&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:restore&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed working with Reidefine LLC on this project and building something a little bit different to other weather apps on the market. You can download &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/solcaster/id1387772375?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;Solcaster on the App Store&lt;/a&gt; for free and learn more about it at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.solcaster.com&quot;&gt;solcaster.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:rain&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’m currently in the middle of a heatwave in Leicester. Unfortunately my nearest rain is in 300 miles away in France… tempting! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:rain&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:previousfuture&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Why the previous weather? If you’re a snowboarder the amount of snow that fell yesterday is probably more important to you than the weather today. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:previousfuture&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:restore&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It is mandatory for iOS apps to provide a “restore purchases” button when using in-app purchases so that functionality can be restored should you delete and reinstall the app, restore from a backup, or update to a new device. My thinking was that it was far better to sync this information through the secure iCloud sync such that this unlocking is seamless. You can try it by downloading and upgrading Solcaster on one device then opening it on another; within a second or two of opening the app you’ll notice the ads pop away without the need to tap a button and sign in to your Apple account. Wonderful! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:restore&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>"iPhone Only" apps on the iPad</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2018/06/20/iphone-only-apps-on-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 12:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2018/06/20/iphone-only-apps-on-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the launch of the iPad in 2010, any app that runs on the iPhone will also run on the iPad in a scaled format. This is normally&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:ipadpro&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:ipadpro&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in the 3:2 aspect ratio which the original iPhone had all the way up until the iPhone 5 when they changed to the 16:9 ratio&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:xratio&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:xratio&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Many developers forget about this fact and happily build their iPhone apps unaware that the App Store Review team will test them on an iPad and reject you if something doesn’t work. The fact that this 3:2 aspect ratio is used has been the bane of my iPhone development life for the past couple of years as even though iOS 10 dropped support for the iPhone 4S you still had to make your iPhone apps run at 3:2 so they could work on the iPad. This is particularly frustrating when designers provide designs at the 16:9 size and you have to find a way to make fixed size assets work on the smaller height without resorting to scrollbars…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like this is set to change with iOS 12 as beta 2 is now running iPhone apps in their 16:9 ratio on all iPads rather than than the 3:2 ratio. Whilst there aren’t any App Store guidelines changes to go along with this, it follows that &lt;strong&gt;if you build an iOS 12 app you no longer need to support the 3:2 screen size&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of one of my upcoming iPhone only apps running on a 9.7” iPad with iOS 11 and one with iOS 12 beta 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2018/ios12ipadscaling.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As ever, things could still change and Apple may reverse this decision in later betas but it seems unlikely bearing in mind this has been standard practice on the 12.9” iPad Pro since launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is still not a perfect solution. I am desperate for Apple to finally stop the ridiculous notion that iPhone apps need to run on iPad. The App Store actively fights against this edge case by requiring you to choose “iPhone Only”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:appstoresearch&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:appstoresearch&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; when searching for iPhone apps so why not allow developers to choose if their app should be able to run on an iPad or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that irks me most about this is that iPhone apps on the iPad are not a good experience. Phil Schiller even &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/L4eZryAFcLg?t=7m42s&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; as much at the launch of the iPad Mini:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’ve learned […] that customers love the ones written for iPad, designed for that screen. What does the other platform have? They have phone applications stretched up; not tablet applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He even shows the Android phone version of Yelp scaled up on an Android tablet versus the native iPad app &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/L4eZryAFcLg?t=8m1s&quot;&gt;saying&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You get a great experience on iPad mini, you get a scaled up phone experience on that other product. It’s a big difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This continues with a number of apps with the message being clear that scaled up phone apps on a tablet are worse than native tablet apps. I couldn’t agree more, Phil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, the change from 3:2 ratio apps to 16:9 ratio is a big win for developers and will avoid a lot of design problems. I can only hope that later Xcode builds will finally allow an option for truly “iPhone Only” builds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:ipadpro&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The 12.9” iPad Pro was an outlier that always used the 16:9 ratio for some reason. Doesn’t really make sense that it got this change first as all iPads are the same 4:3 ratio anyway… &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:ipadpro&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:xratio&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Unfortunately 16:9 wasn’t the end of it and the iPhone X has a new aspect ratio of 39:18 (or 19.5:9 if you prefer). &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:xratio&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:appstoresearch&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Which is a ridiculous name. Why not “iPad Only” and “iPad and iPhone”? If they were truly “iPhone Only” they shouldn’t even show up in the same way that Apple TV apps don’t appear on an iPad! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:appstoresearch&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Intents with SiriKit on iOS 12</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2018/06/05/custom-intents-with-sirikit-ios-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2018/06/05/custom-intents-with-sirikit-ios-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was the start of WWDC 2018 and one new feature in iOS 12 caught my attention amongst the many that were demonstrated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2018/heysiritile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hey Siri, I lost my keys&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demo was part of the new Shortcuts system and showed that apps could reveal some functionality to Siri, in this case the Tile app being able to search for your keys. Once the keynote was over and the documentation went live, I had a dig through and was intrigued to find a new “custom intent” within SiriKit exposed as &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/sirikit/inobject?changes=latest_minor&quot;&gt;INObject&lt;/a&gt;. This is paired with a full demo app in the form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/sirikit/accelerating_app_interactions_with_shortcuts?changes=latest_minor&quot;&gt;Soup Chef&lt;/a&gt; that shows how you can create these custom intents and use them as shortcuts for Siri. The most interesting thing about this is the following concept from the Soup Chef overview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These types define the schema that Siri uses to identify requests the user makes; for example, “Order tomato soup with cheese.” The parameter combination for this example is: soup and options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I dug into the code, I found this new &lt;code&gt;Intents.intentdefinition&lt;/code&gt; file with which you can create custom intents complete with paramater binding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2018/sirikit-custom-intent.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Custom Intent creation with SiriKit&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sure looks like the much anticipated ability to write your own Siri code!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-this-isnt&quot;&gt;What this isn’t&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that isn’t the case. The new custom intents are for “Siri the all-seeing widget assistant” not for “Siri the thing you control with your voice”. These custom intents are designed to be created for very specific use cases and then exposed as shortcuts so that you can access them quickly from your lock screen, add them to a workflow, or activate them with a custom voice command &lt;em&gt;that the user creates&lt;/em&gt;. Despite the schema being present and the documentation alluding to voice control, you cannot create your own custom commands such as &lt;em&gt;“Order tomato soup with cheese”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By way of an example, I have my own app that I use to update my gaming time on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://shyguys.io/recently-played/&quot;&gt;ShyGuys gaming website&lt;/a&gt; and I was hoping to be able to use this system to say &lt;em&gt;“Hey Siri, add 0.8 hours of gaming time to Skyrim on the Switch”&lt;/em&gt;. In parameter based terms this would be &lt;em&gt;“add [hours:decimal] of gaming time to [title:string] on the [console:enum]”&lt;/em&gt;. Unfortunately this is not yet possible although the system shows promise for this future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I go into how this system works and the intended use case, there is one extra thing in SiriKit that will please many developers; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/sirikit/media?changes=latest_minor&quot;&gt;Media Intent Domain&lt;/a&gt; which effectively allows you to use Siri to control media apps such as Spotify, Audible, or Overcast once the developers add the necessary updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;custom-intents-and-shortcuts&quot;&gt;Custom Intents and Shortcuts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are unable to write custom Siri scripts, what then is the point of the new custom intent? It is designed to give you a quick shortcut to commonly used tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways, the Tile app is the perfect demo as it really only does one thing which is to find a specific object. The developers of Tile could create a custom intent of the sort “Find [tile:custom]” and when the app first launches on iOS 12 they can &lt;em&gt;donate&lt;/em&gt; an &lt;code&gt;INIntent&lt;/code&gt; for every Tile that you own; this basically registers the shortcut with the system so you are telling Siri&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:widgetmaster&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:widgetmaster&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that there is a “Find Keys” intent, “Find Remote” intent, “Find Dog” intent, etc. These intents are exposed to the user as Shortcuts both within the Settings app and in the new Shortcuts app&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:shortcutsapp&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:shortcutsapp&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Every time you use the Tile app to find something, the specific intent for that device can be re-donated to the system which helps Siri learn and enables it to prompt you when you may need to do this. For example, if you open your Tile app every morning at 8am and tap on your “Keys” Tile to find it, then that “Find Keys” intent is donated to the system helping Siri realise it should probably show you that intent just before 8am. How does it show an intent? By displaying it as a Shortcut on your lock screen, notification centre, Apple Watch, or within the Shortcuts app where it can then be paired with other Shortcuts from other apps (i.e. you could have an “I’m running late” workflow which sends an iMessage to your boss, activates your find keys intent, loads up your route to work in Maps, and opens the garage ready for you to jump into your car).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The piece that makes this slightly more confusing is that you can add a custom Siri voice command to a Shortcut. When Craig demonstrated saying &lt;em&gt;“Hey Siri, I lost my keys”&lt;/em&gt;, that is really just a voice command on the “Find Keys” custom intent and is highly specific to that particular Tile; you’d have to record a new one if you wanted to find your TV Remote Tile. These &lt;em&gt;Shortcut Phrases&lt;/em&gt; can be created either from within the Settings app or an app can present a view controller&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:inuiaddvoiceshortcutviewcontroller&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:inuiaddvoiceshortcutviewcontroller&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (complete with a suggested command text) that lets the user record their custom snippet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2018/sirikit-shortcut-phrases.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a Shortcut is invoked (either by a Shortcut Phrase or by tapping on a Shortcut) it can either launch your app in the foreground or fire up your &lt;code&gt;INExtension&lt;/code&gt; that will allow you to then return a custom UI directly within Siri. Both have their uses although again they are fairly specific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By way of an example, lets say I order a Chinese takeaway every Friday night&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:everyfriday&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:everyfriday&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; via the Just Eat app. When I place my order, the app could create two custom intents:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A generic intent for the takeaway venue: &lt;code&gt;&quot;Order from [name:string]&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A specific intent for my meal: &lt;code&gt;&quot;Order [menuitems:array] from [name:string]&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first one could launch the Just Eat app and take me directly to the menu for the takeaway I order from so I can peruse and then place my order. The second one would instead be able to place my regular order without opening the app and even provide custom UI to perform an Apple Pay transaction within Siri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is super powerful when combined with other Shortcuts as I could then record a Shortcut Phrase &lt;em&gt;“Hey Siri, it’s Friday Friday got to get down on Friday”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:friday&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:friday&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; which would turn on my living room lights, open up the Netflix app on my Apple TV&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:dream&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:dream&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, lock the front door, and place my Chinese order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that these Shortcuts can be created silently by the app and then donated to Siri so it can then suggest them to you at certain points is also super interesting. Siri already knows to show the Just Eat app in my Siri App Suggestions on a Friday night so having it in the future automatically prompt me to place a repeat order will cut out some time. Once lots of apps add support for this it will be cool and perhaps a little scary to see what regular habits we have that we didn’t even realise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; It turns out that apps have been creating Shortcuts since as far back as iOS 8. If you make use of &lt;code&gt;NSUserActivity&lt;/code&gt; then these are donated automatically when calling &lt;code&gt;becomeCurrent()&lt;/code&gt; or you can use the &lt;code&gt;donate(completion:)&lt;/code&gt; method of &lt;code&gt;INInteraction&lt;/code&gt; since iOS 10 to donate any of the standard SiriKit interactions such as starting a workout, initiating a voip call, or booking a ride. Any app that has done this, regardless of whether it has been updated for iOS 12, will show in the Shortcuts system.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear, this system is not yet at the same stage as Alexa or Google Home. You can’t say “Order half crispy aromatic duck and some egg friend rice from Peking House” without first having already placed that order and assigning a Shortcut Phrase to it. However, the jump to that system suddenly doesn’t seem so far. Siri is already getting all of the data it needs thanks to the intents parameter builder and I can’t shake the feeling that these custom Shortcut Phrases are just going to be used to train Siri to lots of different words over the coming year. There is going to need to be some clever work to avoid collisions&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:collisions&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:collisions&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but on the whole I’m excited to see where this heads next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the topics above are due to be covered at WWDC today and tomorrow at the following sessions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tuesday 5pm: “Introduction to Siri Shortcuts” [&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2018/211/&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wednesday 10am: “Building for Voice with Siri Shortcuts” [&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2018/214/&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wednesday 11am: “Siri Shortcuts on the Siri Watch Face” [&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2018/217/&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, don’t forget to check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/sirikit/accelerating_app_interactions_with_shortcuts?changes=latest_minor&quot;&gt;Soup Chef&lt;/a&gt; demo app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:widgetmaster&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Siri the widget master, not the voice. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:widgetmaster&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:shortcutsapp&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Which is not available in iOS 12 Beta 1. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:shortcutsapp&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:inuiaddvoiceshortcutviewcontroller&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/sirikit/inuiaddvoiceshortcutviewcontroller?changes=latest_minor&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;INUIAddVoiceShortcutViewController&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:inuiaddvoiceshortcutviewcontroller&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:everyfriday&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;And maybe Tuesday night as well. Sometimes. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:everyfriday&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:friday&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kfVsfOSbJY0&quot;&gt;It’s a classic.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:friday&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:dream&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I can dream - this might be possible with the Shortcuts app but we won’t know until it appears in a later beta seed! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:dream&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:collisions&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Even saying “Hey Siri, use Just Eat to order half crispy aromatic duck and some egg fried rice from Peking House” isn’t great as an app name is not unique (only the app name on the App Store is and even then it can’t distinguish between “Just Eat”, “JustEat”, and “Just Eat!”). It’s a solvable problem but it does add an extra layer of difficulty. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:collisions&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developers who work from spectacular locations</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/11/07/infoworld-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/11/07/infoworld-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently asked some questions about how I work for an article about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infoworld.com/article/3236404/it-careers/developers-who-work-from-spectacular-locations.html#slide3&quot;&gt;developers who work from spectacular locations&lt;/a&gt;. You can read the full piece over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infoworld.com/article/3236404/it-careers/developers-who-work-from-spectacular-locations.html#slide3&quot;&gt;InfoWorld&lt;/a&gt; but I’ve put their full questions and my answers below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-work-do-you-do&quot;&gt;What work do you do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I am a freelance app developer working on apps for iPhone, iPad, Apple Watch, and Apple TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whenhow-did-you-go-remote&quot;&gt;When/how did you go remote?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I used to be a Development Manager in a London-based digital agency back in 2009 and when I moved to another agency it wasn’t a good fit (far too many meetings, not enough actual work). I made the decision to go freelance as a PHP developer which necessitated me working from home essentially forcing me into remote work. I was intrigued by the recently launched iPhone and so started to develop for that - thanks to a lucky appearance on The Gadget Show, I’ve been able to do that ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-you-end-up-in-the-location-you-are-in&quot;&gt;How did you end up in the location you are in?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve always worked from home as a freelancer so the location I’m in now is really just because I live here (which was due to meeting my wife). The greatest joy of remote working is that you can literally work from anywhere so whilst I could theoretically work in a hammock on a beach I’m much happier sat in bed with a cup of tea and my laptop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-did-it-take-to-go-remote-buy-a-laptop-outfit-an-office-argue-with-a-bossteam-something-else&quot;&gt;What did it take to go remote? (Buy a laptop? Outfit an office? Argue with a boss/team? Something else?)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The only thing I needed was the confidence to quit my job and base all of my income on freelancing. That wasn’t an easy decision and it was fairly difficult for the first few months but it all worked out in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;have-you-compared-the-economics-of-your-remote-situation-to-your-previous-one-how-do-they-compare&quot;&gt;Have you compared the economics of your remote situation to your previous one? How do they compare?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Initially I was earning a lot less money due to having very few clients and I was paid irregularly compared to a monthly salary. This changed fairly quickly though and now there is no question that financially it was the right decision to make. Even more importantly is the economics of happiness; I am far happier in my life as a freelance remote worker able to choose when and where I work than I ever was working in an office. This is so true that I refuse to work as a contractor in a clients office even if only for a few days as I find I just can’t produce the same quality of work when stuck in an open plan office on a fixed time schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;are-there-hassles-you-didnt-expect&quot;&gt;Are there hassles you didn’t expect?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The biggest problems are distractions and motivation. It is very easy, especially in the first few months, to kick back and do very little work as you don’t feel the need to rush. Then, when you run out of money you panic and work ridiculously long hours to try and get some invoices sent out. Freelancers typically have periods they call “feast and famine” or “rollercoaster dips” but they are generally referring to having enough advance work; my problem was always that I introduced those periods myself by putting things off as sometimes I’d wake up and just want to play on the Xbox rather than writing an algorithm for a social feed. Thankfully I have now gotten myself into a comfortable routine (especially now that I don’t live on my own) and so things tend to be smooth sailing but at the start it was very difficult to stay motivated when surrounded by nice distractions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DrinkCoach+</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/10/26/drinkcoach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/10/26/drinkcoach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to announce the release of a new client app, &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/drinkcoach+/id849022698?mt=8&quot;&gt;DrinkCoach+&lt;/a&gt;, that I worked on over the summer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2017/drink-coach.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on DrinkCoach+ for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.orbismedia.co.uk&quot;&gt;Orbis Media&lt;/a&gt; as a freelance iOS developer. The app was designed for the Haringey Advisory Group on Alcohol (HAGA) and is designed to help people keep a track of their alcohol intake with measurable goals and monitor any events caused by drinking such as moodswings, cravings, or accidents. This is actually version 3.0 of the app with the previous versions having been created by a different developer. The old code was neither available or desireable and so I rebuilt the app from scratch using Swift 4.0 and the latest iOS SDKs to ensure it was future proofed for any future developer to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is optimised for all iPhone and iPad devices (including the iPhone X) and makes use of AutoLayout to scale perfectly across the growing number of screen resolutions and aspect ratios. In terms of functionality, there are a number of interesting technologies used in the app including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local notifications:&lt;/strong&gt; the app can notify you at certain times and even locations to help keep you on track with your goals. This was all done locally on the device so that notifications could be triggered without an internet connection or unreliable push notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infographic generation:&lt;/strong&gt; an infographic detailing how many calories and units you’ve consumed along with your total alcohol expenditure can be displayed in the app and shared as an image.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full customisation:&lt;/strong&gt; the drinks in the app can be customised with specific units, calories, and pricing information so that they accurately reflect your usual tipple. Drinks can also be dragged and dropped so that your regular drinks are easier to access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was really great to work with Orbis Media again and I’m confident that people will love the improvements to this version of the app. You can download &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/drinkcoach+/id849022698?mt=8&quot;&gt;DrinkCoach+ on the App Store&lt;/a&gt; for free and learn more about it at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.drinkcoach.org.uk&quot;&gt;drinkcoach.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing left-to-right text in iOS localizations</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/10/04/forcing-left-to-right-text-ios-localization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/10/04/forcing-left-to-right-text-ios-localization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since iOS 6 it has been the case that any localization that utilises a right-to-left language (such as Arabic) will automatically flip your views so that everything scans from right-to-left. Usually this is desireable but there are certain instances where you may want to disable this functionality (such as with a media player that should scrub from left-to-right). I was recently asked by a client to completely disable the right-to-left functionality for all languages as it was causing too many display issues within the app and customers were specifically saying they’d prefer it to scan that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bit of searching, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/14724767/ios-disable-ui-mirroring-in-xib&quot;&gt;general consensus&lt;/a&gt; was that I’d need to manually alter&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:manualstoryboard&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:manualstoryboard&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; all of my horizontal constraints in order to force them to be left to right rather than leading to trailing which will flip based on localization. In a project with 1000s of these constraints this did not seem a suitable course of action and would require any future developers on the project to keep this in mind when creating new constraints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I came across a property added to UIView in iOS 9 named &lt;code&gt;semanticContentAttribute&lt;/code&gt;. This allows you to choose &lt;code&gt;unspecified&lt;/code&gt; (the default which flips based on localization), &lt;code&gt;playback&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;spatial&lt;/code&gt; which are special cases for media controls or directional controls, and &lt;code&gt;forceLeftToRight&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;forceRightToLeft&lt;/code&gt; which work as their names would suggest. Thanks to the &lt;code&gt;UIAppearance&lt;/code&gt; protocol, disabling the flipping globally is a simple one-liner:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-swift&quot; data-lang=&quot;swift&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;UIView&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;appearance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;semanticContentAttribute&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;forceLeftToRight&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This not only flips all content back to left-to-right but also ensures that your &lt;code&gt;UINavigationController&lt;/code&gt; will animate from left-to-right as well. Of course, you can also use the &lt;code&gt;appearanceWhenContainedIn:&lt;/code&gt; method to limit this global change to specific view controllers of your app should you wish to or to set certain controls to other directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only other thing I needed to change in my project to get this all working was some paragraph styles for attributed strings. I frequently use &lt;code&gt;NSMutableParagraphStyle&lt;/code&gt; to set custom line heights and I leave the other properties to their defaults. One of these is &lt;code&gt;alignment&lt;/code&gt; which is always left on my devices due to my English language but the default is actually &lt;code&gt;natural&lt;/code&gt; which means it renders depending on the language. Searching through my project and finding the few places I’d left out a default and setting it was fairly trivial:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-swift&quot; data-lang=&quot;swift&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;paragraph&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;NSMutableParagraphStyle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;paragraph&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;lineSpacing&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;4.0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;paragraph&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;alignment&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total, I only needed to make 8 edits to my project; much easier than trying to edit every horizontal constraint in your storyboard!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:manualstoryboard&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;If I had gone down that route I likely would have written a build script that would go through every xib and storyboard file and do this for me but I have been burned by manually editing xib files in the past. That’s a young man’s game! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:manualstoryboard&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPMediaItem+CanAddToLibrary.swift</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/07/19/mpmediaitem-canaddtolibrary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/07/19/mpmediaitem-canaddtolibrary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since iOS 9.3 it has been possible to &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/02/23/details-on-ios-9-3-media-library-additions/&quot;&gt;add Apple Music tracks to the media library&lt;/a&gt; as such:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-swift&quot; data-lang=&quot;swift&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;library&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;MPMediaLibrary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;addItem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;withProductID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;entity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;NSLog&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Error: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;\(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;localizedDescription&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is powerful as you can use a simple identifier to both play a song and add it to the library but it is likely that your UI will want to show an add to library button similar to the Music app on iOS. To remedy this, I’ve created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bendodson/MPMediaItem-CanAddToLibrary&quot;&gt;simple Swift extension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:mpmediaitemswift&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:mpmediaitemswift&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for MPMediaItem that tells you if a currently playing track is available in your library:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-swift&quot; data-lang=&quot;swift&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;UIKit&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;MediaPlayer&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;extension&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;MPMediaItem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;canAddToLibrary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;Bool&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;MPMediaPropertyPredicate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;persistentID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;forProperty&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;MPMediaItemPropertyPersistentID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;query&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;MPMediaQuery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;filterPredicates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;query&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;items&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;?.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why an extension on MPMediaItem? The only way to know if a track is in your library is to search the user library with an &lt;code&gt;MPMediaQuery&lt;/code&gt;. Unfortunately you can’t search on  the &lt;code&gt;MPMediaItemPropertyPlaybackStoreID&lt;/code&gt; (as some tracks may not be on Apple Music) so instead you need to use the persistent ID property. If you try and play an Apple Music track using an identifier, then you can retrieve an MPMediaItem and use that to get the persistent ID for searching the media library. I use this in my own apps&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:playlist&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:playlist&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by listening to the &lt;code&gt;MPMusicPlayerControllerNowPlayingItemDidChange&lt;/code&gt; notification and then checking if there is a &lt;code&gt;nowPlayingItem&lt;/code&gt; on my &lt;code&gt;MPMusicPlayerController&lt;/code&gt; instance; if there is then check it to find the current status:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-swift&quot; data-lang=&quot;swift&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;player&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;MPMusicPlayerController&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;override&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;func&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;viewDidLoad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;super&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;viewDidLoad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;player&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;beginGeneratingPlaybackNotifications&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;NotificationCenter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;addObserver&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;selector&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;#selector&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;playbackStateDidChange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;MPMusicPlayerControllerNowPlayingItemDidChange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;object&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;@objc&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;func&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;playbackStateDidChange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;guard&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;player&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nowPlayingItem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// at this point we do not know if the track can be added - any UI for adding should be hidden&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;canAddToLibrary&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    	&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// show your &amp;quot;Add to library&amp;quot; button&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    	&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// show some UI to explain &amp;quot;Already in library&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am fairly sure this is how the Music app works on iOS as you’ll notice when skipping tracks that the UI for the track status is completely hidden until the track is ready to play at which point either an add button or a tick will appear. One thing that caught me out was listening for &lt;code&gt;MPMusicPlayerControllerPlaybackStateDidChange&lt;/code&gt; but this seems to fire inconsistently both on iOS 10 and iOS 11 (unless you are on an iPad and run the Music app in split-screen mode in which case it always works) - checking for &lt;code&gt;MPMusicPlayerControllerNowPlayingItemDidChange&lt;/code&gt; works consistently and will still yield an &lt;code&gt;MPMediaItem&lt;/code&gt; with which to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT:&lt;/strong&gt; The user will need to have granted permission to access their media library in order for this extension to work. It will crash your app if you do not have NSAppleMusicUsageDescription in your Info.plist (although that is the bare minimum - you should actively check for capabilities before using this as no point showing an “Add to library” button if the user doesn’t have that capability!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bendodson/MPMediaItem-CanAddToLibrary&quot;&gt;Checkout the &lt;code&gt;MPMediaItem+CanAddToLibrary&lt;/code&gt; Swift extension on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:mpmediaitemswift&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I wrote the extension using Swift 4 with Xcode 9 / iOS 11 SDK but it should work just fine in Swift 3 as it isn’t using any new language stuff. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:mpmediaitemswift&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:playlist&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Including an exciting iOS 11 only Apple Music app I’m working on. If you’re an Apple Music subscriber with the iOS 11 beta installed (developer or public), &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.com/contact/&quot;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; for a test version before it launches in September… &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:playlist&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flawless</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/06/16/flawless/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/06/16/flawless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the great things about Twitter is the way it can connect you to other developers. For many years, I’ve been chatting with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LisaDziuba&quot;&gt;Lisa Dziuba&lt;/a&gt; and she got in touch with me last year along with her colleague &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ahmed_sulajman&quot;&gt;Ahmed Sulaiman&lt;/a&gt; to tell me about a new app they were working on, &lt;a href=&quot;https://flawlessapp.io&quot;&gt;Flawless&lt;/a&gt;, which has now officially launched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2017/flawless.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flawless is an absolute godsend for developers working on pixel perfect designs. It is a plugin for the iOS simulator that allows you to compare what is rendering on screen with a static image via various different modes and a slider for opacity. In this way, you can make sure that what you have built matches the image precisely. The app is a plugin for the simulator itself so you don’t need to add any extra code or frameworks to your project. It also works with static images&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:plugin&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:plugin&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; so you don’t need to worry how your designs are provided be that by Sketch, Photoshop, or other&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:indesign&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:indesign&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been lucky enough to be both a beta tester and to be interviewed by Lisa and Ahmed about my workflows to help them tweak the app. If you are an app developer that has to work to a fixed design, you should definitely check it out. Flawless is &lt;a href=&quot;https://gum.co/SyRKm&quot;&gt;available for macOS&lt;/a&gt; at the bargain price of $15&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:price&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:price&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and you can find out more (and get a free trial) on their website at &lt;a href=&quot;https://flawlessapp.io&quot;&gt;flawlessapp.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:plugin&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I believe the original idea was to be integrated with Sketch but after they spoke with me and many other developers who don’t work exclusively with Sketch they decided to pivot to being an iOS simulator plugin instead. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:plugin&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:indesign&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I have one client who provides me designs via InDesign and he is also the most likely to create a GitHub issue for a dividing line being 0.5px out of alignment - love ya Niki 👊 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:indesign&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:price&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This has saved me so many subsequent bug follow ups that $15 is almost criminally low. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:price&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great British Bee Count 2017</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/05/19/gbbc-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/05/19/gbbc-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past couple of years, I have worked with Two Thirds Water on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/great-british-bee-count/id880987608?mt=8&quot;&gt;Great British Bee Count&lt;/a&gt; iOS app for Friends of the Earth. Today, an updated version of the app has gone live to support this years count which runs from 19th May until 30th June 2017:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2017/gbbc-2017.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main update has been a completely new design which fits the more modern “flat” design which was made popular by iOS 7 whilst also putting the navigation within easy thumb reach even on plus-sized devices. There are also many new functionality changes such as an improved bee picker and fact files on each type of bee that can give you a lot more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I also needed to migrate the app to Swift 3.1, I took the decision to completely rebuild the app from scratch&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:scratch&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:scratch&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; so I could make use of some newer iOS features such as stack views and improved auto layout constraints. I also made improvements to the way in which content is stored on the device locally in a Realm database making the whole app feel even faster whilst increasing the reliability of sending count information in the background&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:background&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:background&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/great-british-bee-count/id880987608?mt=8&quot;&gt;Great British Bee Count on the App Store&lt;/a&gt; (it’s free) or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foe.co.uk/page/join-great-british-bee-count-today&quot;&gt;learn more about the bee cause&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:scratch&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This was a decision the client was not made aware of and whilst it cost me more time (as I worked to a fixed budget) the end result is an app I can be really proud of. I’d much rather spend a bit more time and money from my own pocket to make something perfect than try and hack something together quickly especially if it is a full redesign of an existing app. Due to changes in the Swift language and a move away from separate xib files to storyboards, I was able to reduce the overall file size by 20% and the amount of code by 45%. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:scratch&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:background&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;For example, if you try and submit a count when you have no network connection, the app can automatically upload this information once connectivity is restored even if it is no longer in the foreground. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:background&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reaction Cam</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/05/10/reaction-cam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/05/10/reaction-cam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m very pleased to announce the release of a new client app I’ve been working on over the past couple of months: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/app-store.png&quot;&gt;Reaction Cam&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2017/reactioncam.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hired by Elliott Brock to build Reaction Cam, an easy-to-use app that allows you to quickly record and share your reaction to anything from video to content in a browser. Due to the limitations of iOS sandboxing, this was an immense technical challenge but the end result is incredibly slick with the power to record a reaction and the content on screen at the same time. Once recording is complete, you can edit your reaction and the content by trimming and rotating as well as swapping what is used as the “picture in picture” recording (or disabling it altogether)&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:pip&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:pip&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. A single file is exported at the end of the process for easy sharing with friends on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supported media for reacting to includes video (both saved on device and online), photos (complete with a swipeable scrolling interface), and a full browser for viewing everything from tweets to blog posts. In addition to the app, I also built an API and an admin system so that Elliott could handpick recommended videos to react to as well as publishing some of the reactions that had been recorded with the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was given a very loose spec and so I designed the app and worked out all of the UX myself; I even designed the app icon! Reaction Cam is built in Swift 3.1 and makes use of the latest features in iOS 10 to allow it to run quickly on all of the various iOS devices with full scaling support for every screen size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed working with Elliott on Reaction Cam and hope that people will find it to be a best-in-class app for reaction recording. You can download &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/app-store.png&quot;&gt;Reaction Cam on the App Store&lt;/a&gt; and learn more about it on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://reactioncamtv.moonfruit.com/&quot;&gt;Reaction Cam website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:pip&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Unlike some other reaction apps, I actually record both the front-facing camera and the content onscreen to separate files rather than simply outputting the front-facing camera into the page and capturing just what is on screen. This is massively important as it allows for editing such as swapping which video is shown in the smaller view (i.e. you might want your reaction to be more prominent), it allows you to move the smaller view around, and it means you can disable one or the other after recording. Of course, capturing both live video and the content on screen separately is a technical challenge but I’m very happy I was able to maintain a 30fps recording from both streams even on the oldest supported device (an iPhone 5). &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:pip&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AlcoPath</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/03/27/alcopath/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 11:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/03/27/alcopath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to announce the release of a new client app I’ve been working on for the past few weeks: &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/alcopath/id1189149217?mt=8&quot;&gt;AlcoPath&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2017/alcopath.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on AlcoPath for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.orbismedia.co.uk&quot;&gt;Orbis Media&lt;/a&gt; as a freelance iOS developer. The app was designed in consultation with the the Nottinghamshire Healthcare NHS Foundation Trust and features a WEKP Cognitive Assessment (incorporating 6CIT, Ataxia test, Opthalmoplegia test, and other associated risk factors) to diagnose Wernicke’s encephalopathy, a Withdrawal Assessment for Alcohol using a revised CIWA-Ar scale, and industry recommended pathways all in-line with NICE Guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is available for free and can be used by clinical staff on both iPhone and iPad thanks to a scaling interface suitable for all device sizes. An A4-sized PDF can be generated with the personalised results of each assessment and this can be printed directly from the app. Push notifications were also integrated to inform users quickly of any updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to render the various assessment questions efficiently and accurately, I built a local PHP-based tool to input the various questions and output a JSON file that the app would then interpret to build each question and the various ways of answering be that with a toggle, multiple selection, or text entry. This prevented the need for the app to connect to an online database but also enabled me to make prompt updates should new questions need to be added or existing questions be edited in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great experience working with Orbis Media on this app and the feedback from clinicians has been great so far. You can download &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/alcopath/id1189149217?mt=8&quot;&gt;AlcoPath on the App Store&lt;/a&gt; and learn more about it at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alcopath.co.uk/&quot;&gt;AlcoPath.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building tools for Kylo Ben</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/02/23/building-tools-for-kylo-ben/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/02/23/building-tools-for-kylo-ben/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been running my &lt;a href=&quot;https://kyloben.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Kylo Ben&lt;/a&gt; website about video games since October 2016 and this year I decided to start doing a weekly update about gaming news and what I’ve been playing. Whilst it is fun to do, it is very time consuming as I need to collate interesting links I’ve found, my articles, podcasts, game releases, games I’ve played, and games I’ve purchased which means an average post will take between 1.5 to 2 hours to write. Being a developer means I can build my own digital tools to help me out and so last week I built a few little tools to help cut that time dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the bigger pieces of the weekly roundup is a list of interesting news that has happened in the world of video games. Initially I would copy and paste the URLs of interesting links I found and save them into the Notes app&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:pocket&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:pocket&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; on iOS or Mac. This worked fine but it was a little clunky and getting the data back out took time as I’d need to open each one to see what it was and then add Markdown syntax to each URL I wanted to use. To solve this, I wrote an iOS app and a macOS app that would provide extensions for URLs allowing me to quickly save them to my database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2017/kylo-ben-ios-extension.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;[app name] would like to access Apple Music&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iOS app is purely a blank view controller with a bundled share extension that looks a little like this&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:codequality&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:codequality&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-swift&quot; data-lang=&quot;swift&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;ShareViewController&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;SLComposeServiceViewController&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;override&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;func&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;isContentValid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;Bool&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;override&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;func&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;didSelectPost&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;extensionContext&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;?.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inputItems&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;NSExtensionItem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;itemProvider&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;attachments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;?.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;NSItemProvider&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;itemProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;hasItemConformingToTypeIdentifier&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;kUTTypeURL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;itemProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;loadItem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;forTypeIdentifier&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;kUTTypeURL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;completionHandler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;shareURL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;APIClient&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;save&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;parameters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shareURL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;absoluteString&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;textView&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;onCompletion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;response&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;
                            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                                &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;controller&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;UIAlertController&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;ERROR&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;That didn&amp;#39;t work: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;\(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;localizedDescription&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;preferredStyle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;alert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                                &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;controller&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;addAction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;UIAlertAction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;OK&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;style&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;handler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;action&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;
                                    &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;extensionContext&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;!.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;completeRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;returningItems&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;completionHandler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}))&lt;/span&gt;
                                &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;present&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;controller&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;animated&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;completion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                                &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;extensionContext&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;!.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;completeRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;returningItems&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;completionHandler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;override&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;func&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;configurationItems&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;Any&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is paired with an &lt;code&gt;NSExtensionActivationSupportsWebURLWithMaxCount&lt;/code&gt; entry in the Info.plist file so that it will activate whenever I try and share a URL anywhere within iOS. If I’m in an app reading an article that I want to save, I simply tap the share icon and then choose the Kylo Ben app from the list as shown in the screenshot above. The URL and title will then be sent to my server for retrieval later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2017/kylo-ben-safari-extension.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;86&quot; alt=&quot;[app name] would like to access Apple Music&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve written a number of Safari extensions in JavaScript before but El Capitan added the option to write native extension in Swift via a Safari Extension bundled with your macOS app. To avoid having to make AJAX calls in JavaScript&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:ajax&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:ajax&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I chose to build a simple macOS app with a Safari Extension that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-swift&quot; data-lang=&quot;swift&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;SafariExtensionHandler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SFSafariExtensionHandler&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;override&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;func&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;toolbarItemClicked&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SFSafariWindow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;getActiveTab&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tab&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tab&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;?.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;getActivePage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;completionHandler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;?.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;getPropertiesWithCompletionHandler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;({&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;properties&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;properties&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;properties&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;properties&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;properties&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Unknown Title&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;APIClient&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;save&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;parameters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;absoluteString&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;onCompletion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;response&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;
                            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                                &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;NSLog&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;PROBLEM! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;\(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                                &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;?.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;reload&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
                            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I click on the controller icon, the method above is called and the URL and title are sent to my server; once completed, the page reloads to show me it has been successful. I spent a long time trying to just get a simple alert to display on either success or failure but I couldn’t get it to work correctly. It is possible to interact with JavaScript and I was able to log to the console but any alert would silently fail. If anybody has any tips on that, I’d &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.com/contact/&quot;&gt;love to know how to improve it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic template of my weekly update is the same every week and I used to use a number of custom MySQL queries to pull out the various information I needed and then write it up manually. Now that I have my links stored in my database, I decided to write a PHP script to generate as much of my update as possible so all I need to do is fill in some of the blanks that aren’t automatically provided (i.e. upcoming game release dates) and write my own thoughts and opinions around the news articles. I have a basic PHP script which runs a number of MySQL queries and then generates a Markdown document like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Introduction...

###News

[Final Fantasy 15&amp;#39;s PS4 Pro Update Out Now, Improves Frame Rate And More - GameSpot](http://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-15s-ps4-pro-update-out-now-improves-/1100-6448025/)

[New PlayStation 4 Pro patch for Final Fantasy XV makes it look worse | Ars Technica](https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2017/02/new-playstation-4-pro-patch-for-final-fantasy-xv-makes-it-look-worse/#p3)

[This tiny Nintendo Switch feature is already making fans super happy - Polygon](http://www.polygon.com/2017/2/20/14668988/nintendo-switch-click-sound-effect-joy-con)

[Alto&amp;#39;s Odyssey awaits, Summer 2017](http://blog.builtbysnowman.com/post/157488116747/altos-odyssey-summer-2017)

[never gonna give you up - What’s In the Box?2?! Take 2](http://tyrod.com/post/157494246009/whats-in-the-box2-take-2)

[Steam Community :: Group Announcements :: Orwell](http://steamcommunity.com/games/491950/announcements/detail/484538095747263770)

[Nintendo tag teams with John Cena for living room-inspired Switch demos - Polygon](http://www.polygon.com/2017/2/21/14682742/nintendo-switch-john-cena)

[Look What Mega Bloks Is Doing To Pokémon ](http://kotaku.com/look-what-mega-bloks-done-to-pokemon-1792555348)

[Pillars of Eternity 2 campaign clears $3 million - Polygon](http://www.polygon.com/2017/2/21/14689394/pillars-of-eternity-2-deadfire-funded-3-million-fig)

[Take a look at how itty-bitty the Nintendo Switch cartridge is - Polygon](http://www.polygon.com/2017/2/21/14691596/nintendo-switch-cartridge-size-comparison)

[Australia Is Coming To Civilization VI](http://kotaku.com/australia-is-coming-to-civilization-vi-1792599435)

[Rocket League Original Minis toys expanding with light-up cars - Polygon](http://www.polygon.com/2017/2/21/14692528/rocket-league-original-minis-light-up-cars)

[Hot and heavy Mass Effect pack comes to Cards Against Humanity - Polygon](http://www.polygon.com/2017/2/22/14698798/cards-against-humanity-mass-effect-pack)

And finally, 

###My Posts
- Making the earth move with Stagehand — &amp;quot;I really like the premise of a &amp;quot;reverse platformer&amp;quot; but there simply isn&amp;#39;t enough content to keep me coming back when it is stood next to _Tiny Wings_, _Alto&amp;#39;s Adventure_, and _Super Mario Run_&amp;quot; [[link](https://kyloben.co.uk/stagehand-review)]

###Podcasts
- Podcast #xx: Title [[link]()]
- Another Podcast #xx: Title [[link]()]

###Upcoming Game Releases
- _Game Title #1_ (date - platforms) [[link]()]
- _Game Title #2_ (date - platforms) [[link]()]
- _Game Title #3_ (date - platforms) [[link]()]
- _Game Title #4_ (date - platforms) [[link]()]
- _Game Title #5_ (date - platforms) [[link]()]

###Gaming Time
This week I spent 9.6 hours playing six different games:

- **Stagehand** (0.5hrs): Text...
- **Rocket League** (0.6hrs): Text...
- **Pokémon Moon** (0.7hrs): Text...
- **Forza Horizon 3** (1.1hrs): Text...
- **SteamWorld Heist** (2.8hrs): Text...
- **Night in the Woods** (3.9hrs): Text...

This week I added 2 new games to my library: _Crusader Kings II_, _Night in the Woods_.

Details on games I&amp;#39;m planning on playing this week...

Until next time, have a great week!

---

_Did you enjoy this weekly roundup? Make sure you don&amp;#39;t miss one by subscribing to [Kylo Ben Weekly](https://kyloben.co.uk/weekly) - it&amp;#39;s this post in email form every Monday!_&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news URLs are simply pulled from the database and wrapped up so that each link uses the title of the page as provided by the macOS and iOS extensions. I will nearly always change the link title (as it’ll be part of a sentence) but it allows me to quickly see what an article is about without needing to open it up and re-read it. The “my posts” section requires no editing at all as it pulls the title, link, and a pull quote directly from the articles I’ve published in the previous week. The podcasts and upcoming game release sections can’t be automatically populated (yet) so I just use placeholder text for these to reduce the amount of effort required. The final section on my gaming time uses a number of queries to get the exact amount of time I’ve spent playing in the past week, adds placeholders for each game so I can write about them, and then lists out any new games I’ve added to my library; all of this is thanks to some scripts I wrote a while back that scrape my Steam and Xbox One libraries to track changes and allow me to render a page showing &lt;a href=&quot;https://kyloben.co.uk/gaming-time/&quot;&gt;my gaming time&lt;/a&gt; for the past few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I’ve finished writing, the Markdown file is uploaded to my server and the weekly update will then appear on the website. I then use Byword’s “copy as HTML” feature to generate a HTML version and use that with Mailchimp to write and send out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kyloben.co.uk/weekly&quot;&gt;email version&lt;/a&gt; of the update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these tools, I can now write my weekly update pretty quickly and only have to focus on what I want to say rather than spending time on copying, pasting, and formatting. If you’re interested in video games, &lt;a href=&quot;https://kyloben.co.uk/weekly&quot;&gt;sign up to the weekly email&lt;/a&gt; as it is the best way to get a digest of what has been happening over the past week as well as seeing what new games are arriving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:pocket&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I could have used a service like Pocket to do this but then I’d have to either use two Pocket accounts or fill my personal account with links that I don’t want to read later. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:pocket&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:codequality&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This is not what I would call production code quality so don’t just wildly copy and paste this into an app or you’ll likely regret it. Works well enough for my own personal use though! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:codequality&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:ajax&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Which is a nightmare when you start hitting cross domain restrictions. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:ajax&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposal for an Erase Data Passcode</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/02/16/erase-data-passcode-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/02/16/erase-data-passcode-proposal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, US-born NASA scientist Sidd Bikkannavar was detained by Customs and Border Patrol agents and told he would not be released &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2017/2/12/14583124/nasa-sidd-bikkannavar-detained-cbp-phone-search-trump-travel-ban&quot;&gt;until he gave the agents the passcode to his phone&lt;/a&gt;. They then took his phone (containing sensitive information from NASA) for 30 minutes before returning it and letting him go. He doesn’t know what information was taken at that point although popular consensus is that the entire device could be cloned within that time period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many articles have been written about this but the one that caught my eye was by Quincy Larson of &lt;a href=&quot;http://freecodecamp.com&quot;&gt;freeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt; entitled “&lt;em&gt;I’ll never bring my phone on an international flight again. Neither should you.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you travel internationally, you should leave your mobile phone and laptop at home. You can rent phones at most international airports that include data plans.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you have family overseas, you can buy a second phone and laptop and leave them there at their home.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you’re an employer, you can create a policy that your employees are not to bring devices with them during international travel. You can then issue them “loaner” laptops and phones once they enter the country.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Since most of our private data is stored in the cloud — and not on individual devices — you could also reset your phone to its factory settings before boarding an international flight. This process will also delete the keys necessary to unencrypt any residual data on your phone (iOS and Android fully encrypt your data).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This way, you could bring your physical phone with you, then reinstall apps and re-authenticate with them once you’ve arrived. If you’re asked to hand over your unlocked phone at the border, there won’t be any personal data on it. All your data will be safe behind the world-class security that Facebook, Google, Apple, Signal, and all these other companies use.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Is all this inconvenient? Absolutely. But it’s the only sane course of action when you consider the gravity of your data falling into the wrong hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen similar &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eagle8/status/831827723039416321&quot;&gt;responses on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; including one that you should use a burner phone with a different sim. This is all massively inconvenient, even if you follow the “wipe everything and reinstall once you’ve landed” method; bear in mind that the average iPhone takes hours to re-download all of its data&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:downloaddata&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:downloaddata&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; at a point when you likely need to get maps, book transport, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My suggestion is much simpler; Apple (and other handset manufacturers) should introduce an &lt;em&gt;Erase Data Passcode&lt;/em&gt;. This would be a user-defined passcode&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:touchid&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:touchid&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that when entered immediately performs a secure wipe of the device in a similar way in which the existing “Erase Data” option works&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:erasedata&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:erasedata&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It would be expected that the device would disable power-off options during the secure wipe so that the only way to stop it would be to remove the battery (which in most circumstances would take considerable time at which point the data would be erased).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a solution that would also work in other cases such as theft, muggings, or a jealous partner. Whilst Apple have long had the option to remotely wipe your device via iCloud.com this has become far less easy to do quickly if you have 2-Factor Authentication enabled&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2fa&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2fa&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; as you may not have access to your own devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve filed a Radar on this issue (&lt;a href=&quot;rdar://30553231&quot;&gt;rdar://30553231&lt;/a&gt;) and would urge any other Apple customers that deem this to be a good idea to duplicate it. Apple goes to extraordinary lengths to protect user data and fight for the privacy of its customers but all of that is pointless if you are compelled to give up the keys to your device&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:xkcd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:xkcd&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It is also pointless to have such powerful devices if we need to reset them every time we travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:downloaddata&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This is especially true if you are data roaming as you usually get the slower speeds not to mention that airports generally have congested networks due to the volume of people. Finally, iOS 10 does a load of additional stuff during the first few days of a new device (like Machine Learning on your entire Photos library) which will cause further battery drain / wear and tear on components. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:downloaddata&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:touchid&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;And optional fingerprint for TouchID devices (i.e. my right thumb unlocks the phone, left thumb wipes it) &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:touchid&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:erasedata&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This is an option within &lt;code&gt;Settings &amp;gt; Touch ID &amp;amp; Passcode&lt;/code&gt; that will trigger an automatic secure wipe of the device if your passcode has been entered incorrectly ten times. I’ve always wanted an option to reduce this to three times. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:erasedata&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2fa&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You have 2-Factor Authentication enabled, right? No!?! Go do that now. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2fa&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:xkcd&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;As usual, &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/538/&quot;&gt;XKCD sums this up nicely&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:xkcd&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Checked Shirt #1 - Lost AirPods, iOS 10.3 beta, App Store changes, and Invoicing</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/01/26/the-checked-shirt-episode-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/01/26/the-checked-shirt-episode-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to announce a new podcast I’m doing fortnightly with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonkneen&quot;&gt;Jason Kneen&lt;/a&gt;; The Checked Shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2017/thecheckedshirt.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every fortnight we’ll be producing a 1-2 hour show around the topics of freelance life, technology (specifically Apple), and gaming. Our first episode is available now in which we discuss the AirPods (and how easy it is to lose them), the new changes in iOS 10.3, the ability for developers to leave reviews on the App Store, invoices with &lt;a href=&quot;http://cushionapp.com/&quot;&gt;Cushion&lt;/a&gt;, and lots of other fun stories and anecdotes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get The Checked Shirt from these fine outlets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-checked-shirt/id1199021663?mt=2&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://overcast.fm/itunes1199021663/the-checked-shirt&quot;&gt;Overcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bouncingfish.com/podcasts/tcs/feed.xml&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; (for other podcast readers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to leave a review on iTunes and follow us on Twitter via &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/thecheckedshirt&quot;&gt;@thecheckedshirt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syncing Apple Music with Spotify</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/01/25/syncing-apple-music-with-spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/01/25/syncing-apple-music-with-spotify/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before Apple Music launched in April 2015 I was a longtime Spotify user and subscriber. I maintained a playlist I affectionately called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/user/bendodson/playlist/0FAo3YjdmPjZSHtLMKnJMS&quot;&gt;Ben Dodson’s Definitive Hits Collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; which contained nearly 45 hours of songs I thought were particularly good&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:criteria&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:criteria&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. On most Tuesday nights, my friend and &lt;a href=&quot;http://connectingtohost.co.uk/&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; co-host &lt;a href=&quot;http://johnwordsworth.com/&quot;&gt;John Wordsworth&lt;/a&gt; and I play a few rounds of &lt;a href=&quot;https://kyloben.co.uk/games/rocket-league&quot;&gt;Rocket League&lt;/a&gt; and we will regularly have the Definitive Hits on whilst we play. There are two issues with this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As I use Apple Music now, I don’t pay for a Spotify premium account and so I have to put up with adverts (which are utterly terrible).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They aren’t in sync so we might be humming (or badly singing) along to a song that the other person isn’t listening to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I could just recreate the playlist in Apple Music to solve the Spotify ads issue but we still wouldn’t be in sync. As we’re both developers, we decided to remedy this problem with a fairly convoluted solution…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic idea is that John acts as the host with the playlist on Spotify (on macOS) playing into his headphones. He has written an app that checks if the track has changed and, if it has, sends the track information to my server. I then use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://affiliate.itunes.apple.com/resources/documentation/itunes-store-web-service-search-api/&quot;&gt;iTunes Search API&lt;/a&gt; to look up the song and find the correct identifier which is then sent to an app on my iPhone via push notification to start the song playing on Apple Music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll run through each piece and go over the challenges that were encountered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;retrieving-track-details-from-spotify&quot;&gt;Retrieving track details from Spotify&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t heard of it before but Apple has provided a tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/content/documentation/AppleScript/Conceptual/AppleScriptX/Concepts/scripting_bridge.html&quot;&gt;Scripting Bridge&lt;/a&gt; since macOS 10.5 which allows you to interface with AppleScript from other programming languages such as Python and Ruby. With this, John was able to write an app that polls Spotify regularly&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:polling&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:polling&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to see if the track has changed. If a change is detected, the title, artist name, and album name are all sent to my server so I can begin the process of matching the song on iTunes. In future, we may add more information (track number on the album, duration, etc) in order to try and match better but this is working well enough currently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding-a-track-on-apple-music&quot;&gt;Finding a track on Apple Music&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is for the server to take the information that has been sent and use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://affiliate.itunes.apple.com/resources/documentation/itunes-store-web-service-search-api/&quot;&gt;iTunes Search API&lt;/a&gt; to try and find a match. This is fairly straightforward and a first draft would send a request like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://itunes.apple.com/search?entity=song&amp;amp;term=never+gonna+give+you+up+rick+astley&amp;amp;country=gb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the iTunes API does not allow you to search multiple terms (i.e. &lt;code&gt;artist=rick+astley title=never+gonna+give+you+up&lt;/code&gt;) so everything has to be concatenated together which leads to an issue; sometimes the song you expect is not the one you get. For example, consider the song &lt;em&gt;She Looks So Perfect&lt;/em&gt; by “5 Seconds of Summer”; If you search for this, the first result on the iTunes API will actually be a the “Ash Demo Vocal” version of the song which is not the one we want. To resolve this, we started sending the album information (in addition to title and artist name) so I could match that manually by iterating through the results; I then only choose the first result if there isn’t a song in the list with the same title and album name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next issue I encountered involves the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romanization_of_Belarusian&quot;&gt;Romanization of Belarusian&lt;/a&gt;; the track &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belarus_in_the_Eurovision_Song_Contest_2013&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Solayoh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is rightly attributed to Alyona Lanskaya on Spotify but Apple Music uses Romanization so it becomes Alena Lanskaya. If you search &lt;code&gt;term=solayoh+alyona+lanskaya&lt;/code&gt; then you get no results. To fix this issue, if no results are returned from the iTunes API then I then do a search for the title alone and return the first result as that works in 99% of cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final issue on the API side revolves around remastered tracks. The song &lt;em&gt;A Horse with No Name&lt;/em&gt; is listed as &lt;em&gt;A Horse with No Name - 2006 Remastered Version&lt;/em&gt; on Spotify but Apple Music doesn’t include that suffix even though they have the exact same version of the album. To fix this, if there are no results returned (again)  then I split the string by non-alphanumeric characters and just try the first part in the lookup. Again, this seems to work in 99% of cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I have a track, I take the identifier and send it within a push notification along with the server time before I started making API calls (you’ll see why shortly). I use a silent push notification via the &lt;code&gt;content_available&lt;/code&gt; flag as I want to wake the app up and run some code but not actually display anything to the end user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-ios-app&quot;&gt;The iOS App&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final piece of the puzzle is an iOS app with a fairly minimal interface&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:switch&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:switch&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2017/music-sync.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key thing for the iOS app to do is to play the track that comes from the push notification. This is fairly easy with an &lt;code&gt;MPMusicPlayerController&lt;/code&gt; but we run into problems when the app is in the background as whilst the app will wake up from the silent push it isn’t allowed to play music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, we can enable the background audio capability that allows us to control audio from the background but it only works if audio is already playing. To remedy this, I play a 5 minute track from the album “&lt;a href=&quot;https://itun.es/gb/6K_2v&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Silent Tracks of Various Useful Lengths&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;” (id #366737838) on repeat so that the app is continuously playing music… it just happens to be silent music&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:silent&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:silent&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a silent push is received, it starts to play the track but it also adds the 5 minute silent track to the queue. This is important as it prevents the background audio from terminating should I have a different length of music to Spotify or if a push is delayed due to network reasons. In essence, a normal track will be played followed by a track of silence whilst it waits for the next notification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final issue to solve is one of latency; there is a lot of latency inherent in this setup as we are polling Spotify, sending data to a server, doing one or more lookups against the iTunes API, relying on a push notification, and finally buffering the song in Apple Music! In order to keep us roughly in sync, the app will connect with my server when enabled and fetch the server time so that it can keep time&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:clock&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:clock&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. When the push notification comes in, it contains a timestamp from when the server was first hit by the macOS app and I can then calculate the offset in order to skip into the track a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, lets suppose John starts listening to &lt;em&gt;C’est La Vie&lt;/em&gt; by B*Witched&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:classic&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:classic&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and his app hits my server at 1485359762 seconds from the unix epoch. This is recorded and sent in the push notification along with ID #298026101. If that process takes 3 seconds, then the iPhone app will know the server time is now 1485359765 and can work out that it needs to skip forward 3 seconds in the song in order to keep me in sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazingly, this crazy system actually works and we are able to have our playlist synced and ad free on two completely separate streaming services. I built my portion of the project as an iOS app as Windows does not have access to Apple Music yet I play Rocket League on the PC; in order to actually hear the audio, I wear a single AirPod in my right ear underneath my Turtle Beach X10 Headset so I can hear the music but still get the audio from the game and Skype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only after we’d got it working that we realised we could have just set up some form of streaming radio server but that likely wouldn’t have been as much fun…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:criteria&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The actual criteria to add songs is simple; I either have to use the phrase “it’s a classic” to be able to describe the song or it has to be “catchy as f**k”. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:criteria&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:polling&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;An improvement would be to hook into some sort of notification so that the app can be told when Spotify changes track rather than polling every second but this works well enough for now. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:polling&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:switch&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The switch simply activates the app as I’m using various background modes and don’t want my phone to randomly start playing music if John is listening to Spotify whilst we aren’t gaming! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:switch&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:silent&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I was originally planning on using the track &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/4′33″&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;4′33″&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; until I found the album of silent audio. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:silent&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:clock&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Originally I would get the timestamp and then start counting it up with an uptime C method. This had some issues when the device was in standby so I made it simpler and I just work out the offset between the system clock and the server date; then, when I want to know what time it would be on the server, I can just add the offset to the system clock. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:clock&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:classic&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It’s a classic. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:classic&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts on Apple's new Alternative Tier A and B pricing strategy for apps</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/01/18/apples-new-app-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/01/18/apples-new-app-prices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple increased their prices for apps in the UK yesterday due to the current changes in the GBP vs USD exchange rate. One of the interesting changes that came with this were two new “alternate tiers” which would allow developers to maintain the previous 79p price point or drop it down to 49p. I was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-38650296&quot;&gt;asked about this by BBC News&lt;/a&gt; and gave this quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I don’t think many publishers will respond to that change. It’s just throwing money away and there’s no reason to give people in the UK a discount. I certainly won’t be discounting my own apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stick by that today as I don’t see why developers should be penalised for Apple adjusting to economic conditions; it is a change in price that UK users will get used to in the same way they did when the lowest tier changed from 59p to 69p and then again to 79p. This is especially true bearing in mind that the US App Store doesn’t have sales tax included whereas the UK does have VAT (so at current exchange rates a $0.99 app would work out around £0.96).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key thing though, and something I didn’t clock onto fully until looking again at the charts today, is that Alternative Price Tier A and B doesn’t apply just to the UK; they change prices in many places such as China, Australia, and Canada but maintain them in other places such as Japan and Denmark. If you went for Tier A you’d be reducing the price of your app by 50% in the UK but reducing it by a whopping 83% in China! There are also a few odd choices such as Canada’s pricing being $1.39 at Tier 1 (which is $0.99 in the USA) but it drops to $0.99 for both the A and B Alternate Tiers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a worldwide developer wondering about which tier to choose, I would urge you to stick with the basic Tier 1 pricing. If you choose something like Alternate Tier B to maintain the old price for the UK, you could be dropping prices dramatically in other regions as well. I’m not sure why Apple decided to introduce these tiers but they are not helpful to developers, especially at a time when we should be trying to get away from the bargain basement $0.99 apps that are so prevelant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Apple want to reduce prices further, perhaps they should start by lowering their 30% cut?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sporta 2.0</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/01/10/sporta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2017/01/10/sporta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to announce the release of a new client app I worked on late last year: &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/sporta/id945757003?mt=8&quot;&gt;Sporta&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/apps/sporta.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;511&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sporta is an app to keep football fans up to date with the latest matches via local notifications in advance of a game. You simply select which teams you are interested in from the Premier League, Sky Bet Championship, The FA Cup, the Scottish Premiership, or international matches featuring England, Scotland, Wales, or Ireland. You can then choose a reminder time prior to the match (from 5 minutes up to 1 week) and the app will automatically send you a local notification to remind you about the match with details of kick off time, the teams involved, and the venue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was originally contacted by the creator to update the existing version of Sporta but I found that the code wasn’t suitable for me to work with due to a combination of out-dated code and offshore developers with poor documentation. Instead, I proposed that re-building the app from scratch with Swift 3 and modern iOS updates (such as AutoLayout to work on all sizes of iPhone and the new permissions systems for notifications introduced in iOS 10) would actually be faster than trying to untangle what was there. I was quickly able to recreate the app and scale it for different iPhone sizes whilst adding an intelligent system for keeping the app constantly up to date; the API for the match updates is called periodically using a combination of Background App Refresh and silent push notifications to ensure that data is always up to date and notifications will always fire at the right time even if the phone happens to be offline&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:offline&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:offline&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Finally, I used the &lt;a href=&quot;http://realm.io&quot;&gt;Realm mobile database&lt;/a&gt; in order to store the match data and be able to quickly execute queries such as “&lt;em&gt;fetch all fixtures that contain teams x, y, and z as either the home or away team&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a really fun project to work on and I’m particularly pleased with how reliable the notifications are. If you are a football fan, you can download &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/sporta/id945757003?mt=8&quot;&gt;Sporta on the App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:offline&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The naïve way of doing this would have been to use standard push notifications from a server at the appropriate times but these are not guaranteed to be delivered quickly or at all. Also, you’d need to send data from the phone if you changed your team selection or notification period whereas with the local database system I created you can do that entirely offline and it’ll just work (as I store all upcoming fixtures locally on the device). &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:offline&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Booktrim for iPhone</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/12/12/booktrim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/12/12/booktrim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m very pleased to announce the launch of a recent client app I developed; &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/booktrim-hassle-free-haircuts/id1130340847?mt=8&quot;&gt;Booktrim&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2016/booktrim.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;574&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booktrim.com/&quot;&gt;Booktrim&lt;/a&gt; is a hassle-free app that allows customers to quickly browse barbershops, book a haircut, and pay right from their iPhone. I built the app in Swift and made use of AutoLayout to ensure that everything scales beautifully across the various iPhone Sizes and I worked closely with Trim Ventures’ API developer in order to ensure best practices. I was also instrumental in the design of the application and making sure that the user experience was optimised for making quick appointments on the go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the app was completed, I was asked to build &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/trimbook-update-manage-your/id1175348893?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;TRIMbook&lt;/a&gt;, an app for barbers which allows them to manage their appointments and availability. Once again, the app was built with Swift and I was key in both designing the UI and ensuring the API was being used efficiently. I worked closely with the Trim Ventures team to publish both apps on the App Store and also to run wider beta tests via TestFlight prior to launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an interesting project to work on and I think the end product works well. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/booktrim-hassle-free-haircuts/id1130340847?mt=8&quot;&gt;download Booktrim from the App Store&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booktrim.com/&quot;&gt;learn more on their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don't be the idea person</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/11/15/dont-be-the-idea-person/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/11/15/dont-be-the-idea-person/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a fan of &lt;a href=&quot;http://dilbert.com/&quot;&gt;Dilbert&lt;/a&gt; since the mid-‘90s&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:dilbert&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:dilbert&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and this week a lot of my friends (and some clients) sent me this strip from &lt;a href=&quot;http://dilbert.com/strip/2016-11-13&quot;&gt;November 13th&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dilbert.com/strip/2016-11-13&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2016/dilbert.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most things, it’s funny because it’s true. I get several of these types of pitches per week and they never fail to amuse me. I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;/weblog/2015/12/22/ios-developers-dont-work-for-free/&quot;&gt;written about this in detail&lt;/a&gt; previously but I still get people who believe they have the next big idea and that it is worth something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideas are worth nothing. Absolutely nothing. It is implementation that is worth something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analogy that I always like to use is that of an architect and a builder. Most software developers are builders that take some detailed plans and create to that specification. The “idea person” should be an architect with a clear vision and enough knowledge to know what can and can’t be done. Unfortunately this is rarely the case. Your typical “build my app idea” guy will have no knowledge of what can and can’t be done and therefore no understanding of the time and complexity there is in turning it into a reality. They just assume that they were the first person to think of a life changing idea and that it will be easy money for whoever builds it. It would be like delivering your kids drawing of a house to a builder and expecting them to have it built, for free, by next week&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:incomplete&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:incomplete&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be taken seriously, do your research. Speak to developers and find out what is and what isn’t possible as the vast number of ideas I receive just aren’t possible given the constraints of software on iOS&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:apple&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:apple&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Then, once you’ve understood the process, either pay a developer for a basic MVP&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:mvp&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:mvp&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; or pitch to investors to get enough funding to build one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t ever be “the idea person” and don’t ever expect other people to work for you for free. The world does not work that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:dilbert&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I have around 14 compendium books of the strips; my favourite is entitled “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Still-Pumped-Using-Mouse-Paperback/dp/B00YDK6RF0/&quot;&gt;Still Pumped From Using The Mouse&lt;/a&gt;” (a reference to a calendar they were making about software developers). &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:dilbert&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:incomplete&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Oh, and by the way, there is a pool at the back and another floor but I didn’t draw that part” &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:incomplete&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:apple&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Can you give me the details for Apple then as this should really be installed by default on every phone - it’s a billion dollar idea”. Genuine email I received when I pointed out an idea wasn’t possible. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:apple&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:mvp&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Minimum Viable Product”, basically a step above a prototype that you can use to gauge interest from consumers and investors. The bare minimum you need to launch. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:mvp&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates to iTunes Artwork Finder</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/11/08/updates-to-itunes-artwork-finder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/11/08/updates-to-itunes-artwork-finder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, my &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.com/projects/itunes-artwork-finder/&quot;&gt;iTunes Artwork Finder&lt;/a&gt; script stopped working due to some &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.developer.apple.com/message/192916&quot;&gt;changes by Apple&lt;/a&gt; with regards to rate limiting. In the past, searching for something on my site would cause my server to send a request to Apple and get the data back but with so many people using it my server would get blocked within a few seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a brief shutdown&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:thanks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:thanks&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I’m happy to say that my iTunes Artwork Finder is now back up and running again thanks to a few tweaks. Now, instead of sending all requests from my server, it works like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you enter a search term (i.e. “Fall out boy” albums in United Kingdom), that is sent to my server where I’ll generate the correct URL that is needed for Apple’s servers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your browser then takes that URL to make the request directly to Apple&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When the data is returned from Apple, the browser then sends it to my server for processing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Results are then displayed!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that there are now 3 network requests instead of 1 but the crucial part is that all requests to Apple’s servers are now made from your own browser so the rate limiting shouldn’t be a problem&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:ratelimit&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:ratelimit&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst not an ideal solution, it does work and means I can keep everything running for a bit longer. I’m hopeful that Apple will alter how their rate limiting works as at the moment it seems a bit broken, especially with it being required for several apps with the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/02/23/details-on-ios-9-3-media-library-additions/&quot;&gt;Apple Music APIs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code for the artwork finder is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bendodson/itunes-artwork-finder&quot;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; although this uses the old PHP request system rather than my new version as that should be more than good enough for personal usage&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:personalusage&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:personalusage&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run into any problems, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.com/contact/&quot;&gt;please get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:thanks&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;During which I received around 80 emails hoping that it would come back online - thanks! It’s nice to know that so many people use the site; I have no analytics on my website so seeing so many people get in touch made me realise how big it has become. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:thanks&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:ratelimit&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Unless you try and do around 50 searches in short succession in which case you’ll need to wait a bit before you can make more requests. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:ratelimit&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:personalusage&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;And if you want to do more than just personal usage you should &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.com/contact/&quot;&gt;speak to me&lt;/a&gt; first as I don’t really want people to create entire duplicates of my own project. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:personalusage&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vortech</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/10/29/dimensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/10/29/dimensions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update &lt;em&gt;(9th Nov 2016):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve updated this article to reflect the new name for the app, Vortech. Whilst submitting a v1.0.1 update (adding support for some extra figures), Apple took issue with the name Dimensions so I had to change it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very happy to announce that my latest self-published app, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dodoapps.io/vortech/&quot;&gt;Vortech&lt;/a&gt;, is now &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/vortech-ability-tracker-for/id1170285044?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;available on the App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2016/dimensions.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;542&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vortech is a character and ability tracker for the videogame LEGO Dimensions. It allows you to easily see all 52 currently available characters (waves 1-6) and 73 abilities and track them in your own collection. Whilst there are other tracking apps available (namely the official LEGO Dimensions app), these tend not to be as easy to use and they don’t allow you to cross-reference the special abilities and powers of characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built the app as I would occassionally come across something that required a special ability and the game might show me a character with that ability. However, as I have a fairly large collection already, it is likely I have a character with the ability and just need to look up which one has it. For example, I might find an area in a level which requires the Sonar Smash ability and the game might show me the character Benny (from The LEGO Movie) as someone with this ability; with my app, I can quickly see who else has that abilty and find I have Marty McFly (from Back To The Future) who will do just as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire app is built using Swift 3.0 and I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://realm.io&quot;&gt;Realm&lt;/a&gt; as a mobile database containing all of the character information that I scraped from the official LEGO Dimensions website&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:legoscraper&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:legoscraper&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I added a few nice touches such as Peek &amp;amp; Pop support for 3D Touch enabled devices and taptic feedback for the iPhone 7 models. The app is completely free and contains no in-app purchases, adverts, or analytics tracking – it doesn’t even require an internet connection!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/vortech-ability-tracker-for/id1170285044?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;Vortech on the App Store&lt;/a&gt; and learn more about it on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://dodoapps.io/vortech/&quot;&gt;Dodo Apps website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find Vortech useful, I’m always grateful for a review on the App Store. If you run into any issues or have feature requests, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.com/contact/&quot;&gt;contact me directly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:legoscraper&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I built a custom scraper using PHP to periodically check the LEGO website and extract the image, abilities, and other information about each character. This then sends me a Slack notification at which point I can regenerate a JSON file and image bundle which I then include within the app. I’d thought about doing push notifications and remote updates for the app but as this is just a free hobby app (and the information only updates every few months) I figured doing it through the App Store will be fine for now. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:legoscraper&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kylo Ben</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/10/27/kylo-ben/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 23:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/10/27/kylo-ben/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have three main hobbies; coding, video games, and LEGO. With the first, I’m fortunate to have a flexible job that allows me to code on tons of different and varied projects every day. With the last, I’ve literally run out of space for the models I already have (most of which are over 2000 bricks in size). Video games, then, are really my main hobby. In the last year I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;http://connectingtohost.com/&quot;&gt;started a podcast on co-operative gaming&lt;/a&gt;, built a powerful gaming PC, and spent somewhere in the region of 900 hours playing games. Today I’m happy to announce a new website I’ve been working on dedicated to my gaming hobby; it’s called &lt;a href=&quot;http://kyloben.co.uk&quot;&gt;Kylo Ben&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2016/kylo-ben.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kylo Ben is divided into several different sections:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;articles&quot;&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently varying between reviews, things I’m excited about, and general thought pieces on the industry. So far, I have published:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A look ahead at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://kyloben.co.uk/titanfall-2-achievements&quot;&gt;achievements in Titanfall 2&lt;/a&gt; (compared to Titanfall)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A review of minimalistic transport sim, &lt;a href=&quot;http://kyloben.co.uk/mini-metro-review&quot;&gt;Mini Metro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A piece about &lt;a href=&quot;http://kyloben.co.uk/my-first-steam-refund&quot;&gt;my first refund on Steam&lt;/a&gt; in 11 years&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some thoughts on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://kyloben.co.uk/thoughts-on-the-nintendo-switch&quot;&gt;Nintendo Switch&lt;/a&gt; announcement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A review of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://kyloben.co.uk/lego-dimensions-doctor-who&quot;&gt;Doctor Who LEGO Dimensions level pack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A roundup of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://kyloben.co.uk/humble-monthly-october-2016&quot;&gt;games in the October Humble Bundle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to write new pieces every couple of days and it has proven to be a good way to practice my writing and get some long form thoughts out that don’t fit neatly into a 140 character tweet. It also means I can keep these game centric pieces away from my more work-oriented blog here at &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.com/&quot;&gt;bendodson.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve listed a few things about my current gaming setups on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://kyloben.co.uk/about/&quot;&gt;about page&lt;/a&gt;. It details the components in my gaming PC, my current console and mobile gaming systems, and a look through the various consoles I’ve owned since I started gaming in 1991.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;games&quot;&gt;Games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a single page which lists all of the games I currently own on both Steam and my Xbox One. Each game has more details including purchase date, last played, total gaming time, and a short note about where I’m currently at with the game. I also list any articles related to that game for easy reference (and vice versa). For example, here is the entry for &lt;a href=&quot;http://kyloben.co.uk/games/mini-metro&quot;&gt;Mini Metro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gaming-time&quot;&gt;Gaming Time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is perhaps my biggest achievement; a complete log of time spent on each game. The page updates daily and will list each game I’ve played over the last 2 months along with duration and a link through to more details. This is done through a combination of two custom scripts I wrote to scrape both my Steam library and Xbox Live / Windows 10 account periodically for changes. It’s been fascinating for me to see exactly how long I’ve spent on certain games (*cough* &lt;a href=&quot;http://kyloben.co.uk/games/peggle-2&quot;&gt;Peggle 2&lt;/a&gt; *cough*) and will allow me to easily write a regular piece on games I’ve played over the previous month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really excited to be writing regularly about my biggest hobby and I’m looking forward to posting frequently for the foreseeable future. I have a few extra things to announce soon including some apps and game mods so &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bendodson&quot;&gt;follow me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for the latest updates. Alternatively, there is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://kyloben.co.uk/rss.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed available&lt;/a&gt; for Kylo Ben which will keep you up to date on any new articles. If you have any thoughts or suggestions for improvements, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.com/contact&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Remotely</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/10/12/working-remotely/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/10/12/working-remotely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently asked by &lt;a href=&quot;http://remote.co/&quot;&gt;Remote.co&lt;/a&gt; to take part in a new Q&amp;amp;A section about remote workers. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://remote.co/remote-workers/ben-dodson/&quot;&gt;read the full Q&amp;amp;A on their website&lt;/a&gt; but I’ve put some of their questions and my answers below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-advice-would-you-give-someone-considering-going-remote&quot;&gt;What advice would you give someone considering going remote?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Discipline. It takes a lot of discipline to work remotely as you’ll find that it is very easy to put off a piece of work when you’re sitting at home. There are no firewalls stopping you from accessing Facebook and Twitter, the Xbox might be sat saying “just one more game”, and before you know it a month has passed and you’ve done nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-avoid-becoming-distracted-when-working-remotely&quot;&gt;How do you avoid becoming distracted when working remotely?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have a pair of noise-cancelling headphones that I bought for working in an open-plan office but they work at home for me as the act of putting them on puts me into “work mode”. The only problem was that if the doorbell went (sidenote: great advantage of working from home is you never miss an Amazon delivery) I wouldn’t hear it; I fixed that by hooking it up to a Philips Hue lightbulb on my desk so I get a visual alert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-you-have-a-dedicated-home-office&quot;&gt;Do you have a dedicated home office?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I do have a dedicated room for work. I have a small desk with a 5k iMac and an external 1080p monitor in portrait mode (I find this better for webpages and iPhone simulators). Apart from the computer, my desk only has space for my tea and water and a Blue Yeti microphone I use for podcasting and Skype. I have lots of bookshelves (mainly full of LEGO) and a small orchid by the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2016/office.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-the-hardest-part-about-working-with-a-traditional-team-while-youre-remote-how-do-you-overcome-it&quot;&gt;What’s the hardest part about working with a traditional team while you’re remote? How do you overcome it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I find the hardest thing is that traditional teams will want to have meetings all the time. They also want you to pop into the office fairly frequently for reasons unknown to me. I’m pretty good at telling prospective clients that I only work remotely and that I don’t do daily catch up calls; I get a good handle for the project and then do a week or two of work before sending over a build for feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MailRoute blacklisting via email</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/09/15/mailroute-blacklisting-via-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/09/15/mailroute-blacklisting-via-email/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://mailroute.net/&quot;&gt;MailRoute&lt;/a&gt; on and off for the past few years&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:sanebox&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:sanebox&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in an effort to reduce the amount of spam in my inbox but there is one missing feature that always drives me nuts; there is no way to blacklist an email address or domain without going to their website. Whilst you can whitelist domains easily from the daily digest of caught spam, there is no feature that lets you forward spam to them in order to have it blacklisted (despite people, including me, &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mailroute.net/entries/23555217-Blacklist-by-email&quot;&gt;requesting it since 2013&lt;/a&gt;). After having a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mailroute.net/forums/21682281-API&quot;&gt;MailRoute API&lt;/a&gt;, I decided it was time to fix this myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several components in getting this working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I created a new email address with &lt;a href=&quot;http://gmail.com&quot;&gt;Gmail&lt;/a&gt; which will catch my forwarded spam&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:gmailspam&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:gmailspam&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I set up an account with &lt;a href=&quot;http://context.io&quot;&gt;Context.io&lt;/a&gt; and connected it to the gmail account&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:gmailaccount&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:gmailaccount&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I put the following code &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bendodson/mailroute-blacklist-with-contextio&quot;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; on a 15 minute CRON job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-php&quot; data-lang=&quot;php&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;?php&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;require_once&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;OAuth.php&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;define&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;CONTEXT_KEY&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;your-contextio-consumer-key&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;define&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;CONTEXT_SECRET&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;your-contextio-consumer-secret&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;define&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;CONTEXT_USER_ID&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;your-contextio-user-id&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;define&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;CONTEXT_TRASH_NAME&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;[Gmail]/Trash&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// change if not using Gmail&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;define&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;MAILROUTE_USER&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;your-mailroute-username&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// should be your email address&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;define&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;MAILROUTE_API_KEY&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;your-mailroute-api-key&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;define&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;MAILROUTE_EMAIL_ACCOUNT_ID&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;your-mailroute-email-id&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// numeric - can be found in admin.mailroute.net network traffic&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$whitelist&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;sending@example.com&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;];&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// add the email address you are forwarding from or you&amp;#39;ll blacklist yourself...&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$inbox&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;performOAuthRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;GET&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;https://api.context.io/lite/users/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;CONTEXT_USER_ID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;/email_accounts/0/folders/inbox/messages&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;foreach&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$inbox&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;message_id&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$body&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;performOAuthRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;GET&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;https://api.context.io/lite/users/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;CONTEXT_USER_ID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;/email_accounts/0/folders/inbox/messages/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;/body&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$content&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;str_replace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;&amp;lt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;str_replace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;&amp;gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;bodies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$emails&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;extractEmailAddresses&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;foreach&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$emails&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;in_array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$whitelist&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;performRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;POST&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;https://admin.mailroute.net/api/v1/wblist/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;email_account&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;/api/v1/email_account/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;MAILROUTE_EMAIL_ACCOUNT_ID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;email&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;wb&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;b&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Authorization: ApiKey &amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;MAILROUTE_USER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;:&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;MAILROUTE_API_KEY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;performOAuthRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;PUT&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;https://api.context.io/lite/users/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;CONTEXT_USER_ID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;/email_accounts/0/folders/inbox/messages/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;new_folder_id&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;CONTEXT_TRASH_NAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;DONE!&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;



&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// CURL&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;performOAuthRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$httpMethod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$headers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[])&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$signatureMethod&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;OAuthSignatureMethod_HMAC_SHA1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$oauthConsumer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;OAuthConsumer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;CONTEXT_KEY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;CONTEXT_SECRET&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NULL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$oauthRequest&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;OAuthRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;from_consumer_and_token&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$oauthConsumer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NULL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$httpMethod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$oauthRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;sign_request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$signatureMethod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$oauthConsumer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NULL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;performRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$httpMethod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$oauthRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;performRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$httpMethod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$headers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[])&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ch&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;curl_init&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;curl_setopt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;CURLOPT_URL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;curl_setopt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;CURLOPT_RETURNTRANSFER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;curl_setopt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;CURLOPT_TIMEOUT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$headers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Content-Type: application/json&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;curl_setopt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;CURLOPT_HTTPHEADER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$headers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;in_array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$httpMethod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;GET&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;POST&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;curl_setopt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;CURLOPT_CUSTOMREQUEST&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$httpMethod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$httpMethod&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;GET&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;curl_setopt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;CURLOPT_POSTFIELDS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;json_encode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$output&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;curl_exec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$httpcode&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;curl_getinfo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;CURLINFO_HTTP_CODE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;curl_close&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;json_decode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$output&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;



&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Email parsing&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;extractEmailAddresses&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$string&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$emails&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;str_replace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\r\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39; &amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$string&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;str_replace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39; &amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$string&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

   &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;foreach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;preg_split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;/ /&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$string&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$token&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$email&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;filter_var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$token&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;FILTER_VALIDATE_EMAIL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$email&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; 
            &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$emails&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;array_unique&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$emails&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now all you need to do is forward any spam you receive to the Gmail account you set up. Every 15 minutes, the CRON job will run and check the inbox for any emails. When it finds some, it will parse them for email addresses and blacklist them with MailRoute before deleting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world, MailRoute would implement a custom email address for blacklisting but this seems to be working for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:sanebox&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I stopped using MailRoute a while back and was using the black hole feature of &lt;a href=&quot;http://sanebox.com/&quot;&gt;Sanebox&lt;/a&gt; but I’ve just stopped using them as found the free service &lt;a href=&quot;http://followupthen.com/&quot;&gt;FollowUpThen&lt;/a&gt; - I was getting a lot of spam after the switch off so decided to re-activate MailRoute this week. I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://fastmail.fm&quot;&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt; for my email in case you were wondering. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:sanebox&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:gmailspam&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;As you’ll be forwarding emails to Gmail, you’ll want to disable its spam filter as otherwise your emails won’t end up in the inbox for processing by Context. To do this, you’ll need to set up a new rule which matches the email ‘@’ and ensures it never goes to spam. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:gmailspam&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:gmailaccount&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Whilst I could connect Context to my personal email and just move things into a folder for blacklisting, I don’t trust services with access to my email account, certainly not services that are free and are using the data. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:gmailaccount&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pocket Rocket for iOS 10 (now with an iMessage app)</title>
      <link>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/09/14/pocket-rocket-for-ios-10-with-imessage-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>ben@bendodson.com (Ben Dodson)</author>
      <guid>https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/09/14/pocket-rocket-for-ios-10-with-imessage-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To coincide with the release of iOS 10, I’m happy to announce a free update is available for my app &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pocket-rocket-quickly-read/id1062699303?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;Pocket Rocket&lt;/a&gt; which includes several new features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2016/pocket-rocket-ipad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, I’ve added an optional tile-based interface which uses an image from the article or a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.com/weblog/2016/09/10/generating-random-colour-with-seed-in-swift/&quot;&gt;random colour&lt;/a&gt; if one isn’t available. You can long press a tile to get options for sharing, archiving, and deleting the article and tapping will open the article up in Safari or the in-app browser as per your settings. Next, I added the ability to share articles directly from Pocket Rocket; whether you are using the old list view or the new tile-based one, just long press on an article and you’ll be given a share option which uses the standard iOS share sheet so you can transfer the URL to any compatible app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I added an iOS 10 iMessage app so you can share articles directly within iMessage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bendodson.s3.amazonaws.com/weblog/2016/pocket-rocket-imessage.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a really interesting feature for me as it let me get to grips with the new APIs that allow apps to hook into iMessage. There are a few interesting niggles for developers when writing these apps&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:niggles&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:niggles&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but on the whole it is fairly simple and includes a lot more power than I thought they would&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:imessagepower&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:imessagepower&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. With Pocket Rocket, you get a list of all of your articles; you can then tap to include them in your message and send them. Once received, you can tap to have the article open up in a webview directly within iMessage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think iMessage apps are going to be a huge deal so I’m excited that Pocket Rocket is one of the first apps available on the iMessage store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pocket-rocket-quickly-read/id1062699303?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;get Pocket Rocket for free on the App Store&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any feature requests or feedback, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://bendodson.com/contact/&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:niggles&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;For example, there is no standard way of seeing when someone tapped a link which is… irritating. Instead you have to work out if a particular message is selected (which happens for a variety of reasons) and then be clever about what you present. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:niggles&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:imessagepower&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’ve seen one app that lets you use the camera within iMessage - pretty cool! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:imessagepower&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    

  </channel> 
</rss>